<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>technology on Contested Thesis</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/categories/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on Contested Thesis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solid Pods - A better place to store user data</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-05-13-solid-pods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-05-13-solid-pods/</guid><description>Solid Pods (Personal Online Data Store) are an open source project from the efforts of Sir Tim Berners-Lee (creator of the original internet) with a goal of re-decentralizing the internet. This project is still in development, I think it has a lot to offer in order to help make developing web applications easier and safer for the developer, user, and society at large.
Solid provides a web standard&amp;rsquo;s compliant API to provide the owner of the pod with an identity (WebID), storage (document store), and relational language for data.</description><category term="technology" label="technology"/><category term="open-source" label="open-source"/></item><item><title>One Wheel Pint - An Honest Review</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-01-02-onewheel-pint-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-01-02-onewheel-pint-review/</guid><description>Commuting is a pain. My particular commute is a multi-stage, adventure that can take an hour on a decent day and mind boggling amounts of time if something goes wrong in Seattle traffic. My spouse and I start by carpooling to our day-care, drop off a kiddo, then catch a bus into downtown, and finally walk across town to my office. Most of the time it works just fine. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much to throw off the whole experience to a post-apocalyptic hell-scape of gridlock.</description><category term="review" label="review"/></item><item><title>The Compliant News Room</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-10-30-the-compliant-news-room/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-10-30-the-compliant-news-room/</guid><description>There has been much ink spilled and great gnashing of teeth over Facebook&amp;rsquo;s news tab and the inclusion of Breitbart as a &amp;ldquo;high quality&amp;rdquo; news source. I continue to be amazed that social media organizations have moved to help establish clear standards and certification for what counts as a high quality newsroom.
In Enterprise software if you want large companies (like Facebook) to buy your software or services, you will eventually have to get a compliance attestation from a third party auditor that your company follows industry standard practices around code development, testing, deployment, and security.</description><category term="society" label="society"/><category term="news" label="news"/></item><item><title>The Email Interview</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-07-10-the-email-interview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-07-10-the-email-interview/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like conducting interviews. I would rather be interviewed for a job than interview someone for a job. If I have to choose between written and oral communication, I will usually prefer to write. I like async communication because I have time to think clearly and then commit to words what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking. I have a mild central auditory processing disorder, meaning an in-person interview pushes my limits of listening, and critically processing, and taking notes on answers in real time.</description><category term="technology" label="technology"/></item></channel></rss>