<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Society on Nortrup in Development</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/society/</link><description>Recent content in Society on Nortrup in Development</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Compliant News Room</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-10-30-the-compliant-news-room/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-10-30-the-compliant-news-room/</guid><description>&lt;p>There has been much ink spilled and great gnashing of teeth over Facebook&amp;rsquo;s news tab and the inclusion of Breitbart as a &amp;ldquo;high quality&amp;rdquo; news source. I continue to be amazed that social media organizations have moved to help establish clear standards and certification for what counts as a high quality newsroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Enterprise software if you want large companies (like Facebook) to buy your software or services, you will eventually have to get a compliance attestation from a third party auditor that your company follows industry standard practices around code development, testing, deployment, and security. Depending on who your potential customers are there are a cornucopia of potential certifications, SOC2, ISO (lots of these actually), HIPAA for health, PCI for credit cards, FedRAMP for the U.S. Federal government. All of these standards provide you a checklist practices that you have to demonstrate your compliance with, then you find an auditor to come in, look at your books and ask you to prove that you follow your own stated policies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>