<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Product Operations on Nortrup in Development</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/categories/product-operations/</link><description>Recent content in Product Operations on Nortrup in Development</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 20:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/categories/product-operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Productboard Field Descriptions and Process Documentation</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/productboard-field-descriptions-and-process-documentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/productboard-field-descriptions-and-process-documentation/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Productboard a lot in the past few months. Purchasing and helping Tanium implement it has been one of my primary tools to help improve our prioritization, process, and transparency with the rest of the organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite things about Productboard is the ability to super easily document what fields are and how they are supposed to be used immediately inside of the product. I use this all the time to both make my life easier as the person building systems, and it lowers the adoption curve quite a bit for my users. It also feels like a good example of your &lt;a href="https://www.rubick.com/engineering-handbook/">process being open source.&lt;/a> Where it is clear it is easy update your process documentation.&lt;/p></description><category term="product-operations" label="Product Operations"/><category term="productboard" label="Productboard"/></item><item><title>Tensions in Product Ops Tool Design</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/tension-in-product-ops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 08:11:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/tension-in-product-ops/</guid><description>I think my core challenge with Product Ops, particularly standing it up from scratch, is the tension for modeling systems and processes as they are now vs how I want them to be. Paired with the tension between how much we need to change and how fast the organization is able to absorb change.
Especially as the guardian and manager of the product tool stack. I know that if I set up the tools the way we work now, then everyone will continue the way we are now.</description><category term="product-ops" label="Product Ops"/><category term="product-operations" label="Product Operations"/><category term="product-management" label="Product Management"/></item><item><title>Product Operations First Take</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/product-ops-first-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 21:36:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/product-ops-first-take/</guid><description>I recently took on the role of Product Operations at Tanium. Which has been a wild ride and one of my most exciting things I&amp;rsquo;ve done in product in a long time. Here are some early notes by way of an experience report for others who might end up walking this path.
Some context; when I started this role, I had been at Tanium for two and a half years which is a good amount of time to learn the ins and the outs of the organization.</description><category term="product-management" label="Product Management"/><category term="product-operations" label="Product Operations"/><category term="product-ops" label="Product Ops"/></item></channel></rss>