<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>product-management on Contested Thesis</title>
    <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/product-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in product-management on Contested Thesis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/product-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I look for in Flow Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2021-10-31-what-i-look-for-in-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2021-10-31-what-i-look-for-in-flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pulling and analyzing Mik Kirsten&amp;rsquo;s Flow Framework metrics for several months at work.  I do this with an incredibly ugly Clojure script that I wrote to learn Clojure.  But I do think the metrics themselves have been a helpful lens to look at what is happening.  Here are some of the questions I ask myself when I sit down to analyze the metrics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with your process</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2021-08-27-experiment-with-your-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2021-08-27-experiment-with-your-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke recently with someone who was new to Product Management and was trying to learn how to do the job by reading blogs and books that talk about everyone&amp;rsquo;s ideal nirvana of product management. As he compared that with his organization (a large, well-respected company), he was distressed at the difference between what they saw and what they understood to be best practice.  He was even debating if he should leave his current gig to work somewhere he could learn and practice this best-in-class PM craft.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Global Priorities</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-12-14-against-global-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-12-14-against-global-priorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with some stakeholders on how we do prioritization as a Product Management team.  I started by trying to build a matrix that would serve as an easy key for keeping product managers mostly on the same page for setting the priority field in JIRA.  I think there is value in having common standards.  But the more I thought about the problem, I got more uncomfortable, because we can&amp;rsquo;t prioritize globally and take into account local context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outcome First Roadmaps</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-11-16-outcomes-first-roadmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-11-16-outcomes-first-roadmaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve talked to me recently you&amp;rsquo;ve heard my song and dance on outcomes based road mapping.  As I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about it over the past few weeks something really clicked for me on why it&amp;rsquo;s so important to identify the outcomes early in the definition of an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are trying to get work prioritized and on the road map, it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to start with a name for the solution that conveys meaning and then find supporters who also like the sound of the idea.  An easy default is to talk about the solution you are proposing to fix a problem.  They go together to help form a narrative story that works well in a meeting.  We have this problem, and here is the solution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is really appealing, it also leaves us some challenges on the backend.  If we prioritize problems with a measurement of what we are going to achieve better alignment on why we are trying to solve this problem, and allow ourselves more freedom to discover the right solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Product Integrations Journey</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-09-28-enterprise-integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-09-28-enterprise-integrations/</guid>
      <description>If you start building an enterprise product eventually you are going to get asked to start building integrations with other enterprise products. This is ultimately an essential evil. Your customers already have a host of enterprise products handling the rest of their workflow. Your product is looking to do something with data coming from or going to another part of the business workflow. No one wants to reenter all of their data into a new system by hand, you need to be part of the ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Military to Product Management - Level Equivalents</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-06-06-military-to-pm-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-06-06-military-to-pm-levels/</guid>
      <description>Military officers interested in moving into technology should consider careers in Product Management. There are strong parallels between the roles and product management requires many of the skill sets that effective officers have developed in their time in the service. But believing that you would be a good product manager and actually getting your foot in the door for an interview is another story.
When applying for roles, I recommend listing your experience in the military as a Product Manager rather than as a &amp;ldquo;Company Commander&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Platoon Leader&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Self Taught Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-02-11-self-taught-pm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2020-02-11-self-taught-pm/</guid>
      <description>I made a career transition into Product Management four years ago. Prior to starting my first role at Splunk as a line level Product Manager my previous experience was in the U.S. Army. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that product management was a career field option when I started my job search, and as I look back on it I&amp;rsquo;m amazed I got any interviews at all. I had no meaningful experience building software, and I made some blind assertions that I had qualifying experience as an Army Officer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Product Manager as Scout</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2019-07-06-product-managers-as-scouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2019-07-06-product-managers-as-scouts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a product manager for three and a half years after being an Army officer for eight. Never in that time have I felt like I truly owned all of the products I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. I’ve never had the final say in everything, and I’ve never sat to review that every single story met all of the acceptance criteria. Time, team dynamics, and the nature of working on large complex products precludes any single person from being able to exert that level of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chief Devil’s Advocate</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2018-01-08-chief-devils-advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2018-01-08-chief-devils-advocate/</guid>
      <description>Watching the aggressive use of Facebook, Twitter, Reddit to disrupt American political and social systems makes me think that organizations above a certain size should have a Chief Devil’s Advocate on their team. This exec should be focused on every way that your product could be used for misdeeds.
The term Devil’s Advocate is commonly used when someone wants to sound smart in a meeting by being contrary about the topic under discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Improvement — A journey</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2017-04-27-continuous-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/product-management/2017-04-27-continuous-improvement/</guid>
      <description>I listened to a great episode of Deliver It on DevOps for Product Owners and a comment by the Lee Janson that you don’t have to have perfect DevOps practices right away really struck home with me. Upon reflection it exactly maps to the evolution that my team has been going through over the past year on our developer tool Splunk AppInspect.
AppInspect is a tool that has grown tremendously in my year with Splunk from a something we built for internal assessment of apps that applied for our Certification Program, to a tool publically available that as both a standalone CLI tool or through an REST API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a military officer should be your Product Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.nortrup.dev/2015-12-05-why-a-military-officer-should-be-your-product-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/2015-12-05-why-a-military-officer-should-be-your-product-manager/</guid>
      <description>Ken Norton in an effort to help companies understand how to hire product managers wrote a guide: How to Hire a Product Manager I’m here to argue that the person you are looking for might just be a transitioning or former military officer. I have never been a Product Manager, but I have spent the last eight years as an officer in the United States Army, I’ve had the pleasure of working with some amazing peers and the honor of leading, coaching and mentoring some very promising young lieutenants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
