<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>WSJF on Contested Thesis</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/wsjf/</link><description>Recent content in WSJF on Contested Thesis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/wsjf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manipulating the Sorted Backlog</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/manipulating-the-sorted-backlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/manipulating-the-sorted-backlog/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written recent guides to creating a backlog from scratch and sorting your backlog by value and effort. As part of building and sorting the ideas and initiatives on your roadmap you will start to show that roadmap to other people. When you do people will have opinions about the order that you have sorted things in. In most cases their opinion will either be agreement, or more commonly, they would like the thing that is important to them to be higher on the list.</description></item><item><title>Quick prioritization of a backlog</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/quick-prioritization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/quick-prioritization/</guid><description>There is a lot of complexity in Product Management, but at the very heart of it what we look to do is order all of the things we could be doing to produce the most value possible. To do that we have to carefully weight the balance of value to effort in order to properly sequence the infinite set of work that we could be doing.
Estimating is a tricky and messy business, and I&amp;rsquo;m frequently skeptical of.</description></item><item><title>Roadmaps From Scratch</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-04-01-roadmap-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 18:42:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-04-01-roadmap-from-scratch/</guid><description>Very rarely will you build a roadmap from absolute scratch. But the technique is helpful because you can apply the process to help rationalize or refit an existing roadmap. I&amp;rsquo;m a strong believer that you should be able to connect all the work you are doing from top to bottom of the company. A developer should be able to look at any task and put it into the context of the larger solution they are building, the problem it solves for the customer, and the business objective that it supports.</description></item></channel></rss>