<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Prioritization on Nortrup in Development</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/prioritization/</link><description>Recent content in Prioritization on Nortrup in Development</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/tags/prioritization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manipulating the Sorted Backlog</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/manipulating-the-sorted-backlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/manipulating-the-sorted-backlog/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve written recent guides to creating a &lt;a href="https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-04-01-roadmap-from-scratch/">backlog from scratch&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/quick-prioritization/">sorting your backlog&lt;/a> by value and effort. As part of building and sorting the ideas and initiatives on your roadmap you will start to show that roadmap to other people. When you do people will have opinions about the order that you have sorted things in. In most cases their opinion will either be agreement, or more commonly, they would like the thing that is important to them to be higher on the list. These differing opinions are good, this is why we build a roadmap. It is better to have those discussions when we are thinking about building things then after we have spent time building something.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Against Global Priorities</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-12-14-against-global-priorities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-12-14-against-global-priorities/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with some stakeholders on how we do prioritization as a Product Management team. I started by trying to build a matrix that would serve as an easy key for keeping product managers mostly on the same page for setting the priority field in JIRA. I think there is value in having common standards. But the more I thought about the problem, I got more uncomfortable, because we can&amp;rsquo;t prioritize globally and take into account local context.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>