<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Contested Thesis</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Contested Thesis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:23:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making Yourself Disposable</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/making-yourself-disposable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:23:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/making-yourself-disposable/</guid><description>One of the best leaders I ever worked with was my first XO at 1-14th Cavalry David Polizzotti. One day while we were deployed to Afghanistan I was stressing about something and he very calmly looked at me and told me that I needed to do a better job at accepting that I as an individual was a wholly replaceable cog in the machine. At the time that felt like a hard thing to swallow.</description></item><item><title>Manipulating the Sorted Backlog</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/manipulating-the-sorted-backlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/manipulating-the-sorted-backlog/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written recent guides to creating a backlog from scratch and sorting your backlog by value and effort. As part of building and sorting the ideas and initiatives on your roadmap you will start to show that roadmap to other people. When you do people will have opinions about the order that you have sorted things in. In most cases their opinion will either be agreement, or more commonly, they would like the thing that is important to them to be higher on the list.</description></item><item><title>Quick prioritization of a backlog</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/quick-prioritization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:34:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/quick-prioritization/</guid><description>There is a lot of complexity in Product Management, but at the very heart of it what we look to do is order all of the things we could be doing to produce the most value possible. To do that we have to carefully weight the balance of value to effort in order to properly sequence the infinite set of work that we could be doing.
Estimating is a tricky and messy business, and I&amp;rsquo;m frequently skeptical of.</description></item><item><title>Roadmaps From Scratch</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-04-01-roadmap-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 18:42:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-04-01-roadmap-from-scratch/</guid><description>Very rarely will you build a roadmap from absolute scratch. But the technique is helpful because you can apply the process to help rationalize or refit an existing roadmap. I&amp;rsquo;m a strong believer that you should be able to connect all the work you are doing from top to bottom of the company. A developer should be able to look at any task and put it into the context of the larger solution they are building, the problem it solves for the customer, and the business objective that it supports.</description></item><item><title>Product Management Scale Up</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-03-07-pm-scale-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2022-03-07-pm-scale-up/</guid><description>&lt;p>In several PM Communities I frequent I see people who constantly ask, should I take a job a this series A or B startup, or a job at some extreme scale public cloud or tech company. Every time I see it I&amp;rsquo;m confused by it because I think of those companies being so far apart in experience that you should spend your time clarifying what you want in a job before trying to pick one or the other. In a hyperscale company there is tremendous specialization for products with billions of users. At a small start up it&amp;rsquo;s all generalists.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I look for in Flow Metrics</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2021-10-31-what-i-look-for-in-flow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2021-10-31-what-i-look-for-in-flow/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been pulling and analyzing Mik Kirsten&amp;rsquo;s Flow Framework metrics for several months at work. I do this with an incredibly ugly Clojure script that I wrote to learn Clojure. But I do think the metrics themselves have been a helpful lens to look at what is happening. Here are some of the questions I ask myself when I sit down to analyze the metrics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Experimenting with your process</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2021-08-27-experiment-with-your-process/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2021-08-27-experiment-with-your-process/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spoke recently with someone who was new to Product Management and was trying to learn how to do the job by reading blogs and books that talk about everyone&amp;rsquo;s ideal nirvana of product management. As he compared that with his organization (a large, well-respected company), he was distressed at the difference between what they saw and what they understood to be best practice. He was even debating if he should leave his current gig to work somewhere he could learn and practice this best-in-class PM craft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Against Global Priorities</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-12-14-against-global-priorities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-12-14-against-global-priorities/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with some stakeholders on how we do prioritization as a Product Management team. I started by trying to build a matrix that would serve as an easy key for keeping product managers mostly on the same page for setting the priority field in JIRA. I think there is value in having common standards. But the more I thought about the problem, I got more uncomfortable, because we can&amp;rsquo;t prioritize globally and take into account local context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Outcome First Roadmaps</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-11-16-outcomes-first-roadmaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-11-16-outcomes-first-roadmaps/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve talked to me recently you&amp;rsquo;ve heard my song and dance on outcomes based road mapping. As I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about it over the past few weeks something really clicked for me on why it&amp;rsquo;s so important to identify the outcomes early in the definition of an idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are trying to get work prioritized and on the road map, it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to start with a name for the solution that conveys meaning and then find supporters who also like the sound of the idea. An easy default is to talk about the solution you are proposing to fix a problem. They go together to help form a narrative story that works well in a meeting. We have this problem, and here is the solution!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this is really appealing, it also leaves us some challenges on the backend. If we prioritize problems with a measurement of what we are going to achieve better alignment on why we are trying to solve this problem, and allow ourselves more freedom to discover the right solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enterprise Product Integrations Journey</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-09-28-enterprise-integrations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-09-28-enterprise-integrations/</guid><description>If you start building an enterprise product eventually you are going to get asked to start building integrations with other enterprise products. This is ultimately an essential evil. Your customers already have a host of enterprise products handling the rest of their workflow. Your product is looking to do something with data coming from or going to another part of the business workflow. No one wants to reenter all of their data into a new system by hand, you need to be part of the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Military to Product Management - Level Equivalents</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-06-06-military-to-pm-levels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-06-06-military-to-pm-levels/</guid><description>Military officers interested in moving into technology should consider careers in Product Management. There are strong parallels between the roles and product management requires many of the skill sets that effective officers have developed in their time in the service. But believing that you would be a good product manager and actually getting your foot in the door for an interview is another story.
When applying for roles, I recommend listing your experience in the military as a Product Manager rather than as a &amp;ldquo;Company Commander&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Platoon Leader&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Solid Pods - A better place to store user data</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-05-13-solid-pods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-05-13-solid-pods/</guid><description>Solid Pods (Personal Online Data Store) are an open source project from the efforts of Sir Tim Berners-Lee (creator of the original internet) with a goal of re-decentralizing the internet. This project is still in development, I think it has a lot to offer in order to help make developing web applications easier and safer for the developer, user, and society at large.
Solid provides a web standard&amp;rsquo;s compliant API to provide the owner of the pod with an identity (WebID), storage (document store), and relational language for data.</description></item><item><title>The Self Taught Product Manager</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-02-11-self-taught-pm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2020-02-11-self-taught-pm/</guid><description>I made a career transition into Product Management four years ago. Prior to starting my first role at Splunk as a line level Product Manager my previous experience was in the U.S. Army. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that product management was a career field option when I started my job search, and as I look back on it I&amp;rsquo;m amazed I got any interviews at all. I had no meaningful experience building software, and I made some blind assertions that I had qualifying experience as an Army Officer.</description></item><item><title>One Wheel Pint - An Honest Review</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-01-02-onewheel-pint-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2020-01-02-onewheel-pint-review/</guid><description>Commuting is a pain. My particular commute is a multi-stage, adventure that can take an hour on a decent day and mind boggling amounts of time if something goes wrong in Seattle traffic. My spouse and I start by carpooling to our day-care, drop off a kiddo, then catch a bus into downtown, and finally walk across town to my office. Most of the time it works just fine. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much to throw off the whole experience to a post-apocalyptic hell-scape of gridlock.</description></item><item><title>The Compliant News Room</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-10-30-the-compliant-news-room/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-10-30-the-compliant-news-room/</guid><description>There has been much ink spilled and great gnashing of teeth over Facebook&amp;rsquo;s news tab and the inclusion of Breitbart as a &amp;ldquo;high quality&amp;rdquo; news source. I continue to be amazed that social media organizations have moved to help establish clear standards and certification for what counts as a high quality newsroom.
In Enterprise software if you want large companies (like Facebook) to buy your software or services, you will eventually have to get a compliance attestation from a third party auditor that your company follows industry standard practices around code development, testing, deployment, and security.</description></item><item><title>The Email Interview</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-07-10-the-email-interview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/technology/2019-07-10-the-email-interview/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like conducting interviews. I would rather be interviewed for a job than interview someone for a job. If I have to choose between written and oral communication, I will usually prefer to write. I like async communication because I have time to think clearly and then commit to words what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking. I have a mild central auditory processing disorder, meaning an in-person interview pushes my limits of listening, and critically processing, and taking notes on answers in real time.</description></item><item><title>The Product Manager as Scout</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2019-07-06-product-managers-as-scouts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2019-07-06-product-managers-as-scouts/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a product manager for three and a half years after being an Army officer for eight. Never in that time have I felt like I truly owned all of the products I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. I’ve never had the final say in everything, and I’ve never sat to review that every single story met all of the acceptance criteria. Time, team dynamics, and the nature of working on large complex products precludes any single person from being able to exert that level of control.</description></item><item><title>Chief Devil’s Advocate</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2018-01-08-chief-devils-advocate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2018-01-08-chief-devils-advocate/</guid><description>Watching the aggressive use of Facebook, Twitter, Reddit to disrupt American political and social systems makes me think that organizations above a certain size should have a Chief Devil’s Advocate on their team. This exec should be focused on every way that your product could be used for misdeeds.
The term Devil’s Advocate is commonly used when someone wants to sound smart in a meeting by being contrary about the topic under discussion.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Improvement — A journey</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2017-04-27-continuous-improvement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2017-04-27-continuous-improvement/</guid><description>I listened to a great episode of Deliver It on DevOps for Product Owners and a comment by the Lee Janson that you don’t have to have perfect DevOps practices right away really struck home with me. Upon reflection it exactly maps to the evolution that my team has been going through over the past year on our developer tool Splunk AppInspect.
AppInspect is a tool that has grown tremendously in my year with Splunk from a something we built for internal assessment of apps that applied for our Certification Program, to a tool publically available that as both a standalone CLI tool or through an REST API.</description></item><item><title>Why a military officer should be your Product Manager</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2015-12-05-why-a-military-officer-should-be-your-product-manager/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/product-management/2015-12-05-why-a-military-officer-should-be-your-product-manager/</guid><description>Ken Norton in an effort to help companies understand how to hire product managers wrote a guide: How to Hire a Product Manager I’m here to argue that the person you are looking for might just be a transitioning or former military officer. I have never been a Product Manager, but I have spent the last eight years as an officer in the United States Army, I’ve had the pleasure of working with some amazing peers and the honor of leading, coaching and mentoring some very promising young lieutenants.</description></item><item><title>Army Brigades are built on agile.</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/military/2015-04-30-army-brigades-are-built-on-agile/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/military/2015-04-30-army-brigades-are-built-on-agile/</guid><description>&lt;p>Michael Cata’s wrote a smart &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@michaelccata/joint-forces-of-change-fe109acf2885">article&lt;/a> discussing the Department of Defense is reacting to changing events with agility. He thinks we have a good start in the &lt;a href="http://www.arcic.army.mil/Concepts/operating.aspx">Army Operating Concept&lt;/a>. In good units the Army already operates as an agile and learning organization. When lead by astute and prudent leaders it can very closely resemble an organization applying the &lt;a href="http://www.scrumguides.org">Scrum Methodology&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sequence Diagrams and better operations planning.</title><link>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/military/2015-04-05-sequence-diagrams-and-better-operations-planning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nortrup.dev/posts/military/2015-04-05-sequence-diagrams-and-better-operations-planning/</guid><description>I’ve helped plan brigade and battalion level operations in my time as a staff officer and company commander. Lots of staff officers and NCOs standing over a map, drawing symbols on acetate, scribbling notes on paper and into emails and documents. Once the drawing is done one or several staff officers walks away from the table and copies all of the graphics onto power point slides and the Command Post of the Future (CPoF).</description></item></channel></rss>